brownpapertickets.com 2019-04-11

# Brown Paper Tickets - The fair-trade ticketing company.

Brown Paper Tickets is committed to transparency in regard to how we treat personal and business information that is collected through our ticketing and registration platform. 

This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, process, and disclose your information, including personal information, when you access and use the Brown Paper Tickets ticketing and registration services.

* * *

  * This Privacy Policy covers how Brown Paper Tickets treats personally identifiable information and all other private information collected on the Brown Paper Tickets ticketing and registration system, whether that information is collected via the Brown Paper Tickets website, mobile service, or call center. 
  * This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of Event Organizers, and/or third party companies that Brown Paper Tickets does not own or control. 

* * *

When this policy mentions "Brown Paper Tickets," "we," "us," or "our," it refers to the Brown Paper Tickets, LLC. Brown Paper Tickets also has a subsidiary, Brown Paper Tickets LTD, based in the United Kingdom. Contact information as follows:

Brown Paper Tickets, LLC  
220 Nickerson St  
Seattle, WA 98109  
United States  
Phone: 800-838-3006 

Brown Paper Tickets, LTD  
17-19 Maritime Lane  
EDINBURGH  
EH6 6RZ  
United Kingdom  
Phone: 0800 411 8881 

Brown Paper Tickets acts as both a "data processor" and a "data controller". Brown Paper Tickets is a data processor because our service offers a ticketing and registration system for Event Organizers to sell tickets or admission, and collect data about their attendees to admit and communicate with ticket buyers or event attendees. Brown Paper Tickets is a data controller because the information provided by Event Organizers, ticket buyers, and attendees is stored with Brown Paper Tickets to record payment transactions and attendee information.

* * *

We use, store, and process information, including personal information, about you to provide, understand, improve, and develop the Brown Paper Tickets website and services, create and maintain a trusted and safer environment, and comply with our legal obligations.

**Brown Paper Tickets collects your data in two primary ways:**

**1.1 Information You Provide to Brown Paper Tickets**

Some information is necessary to use the Brown Paper Tickets system. The following personal and business information is necessary in order for the Brown Paper Tickets services to work as needed.

  * **Account Information.** When you sign up for a Brown Paper Tickets account, we require certain information such as your email address, first name, last name, telephone number. 
  * **Additional Account and Payment Information.** To use certain features of the Brown Paper Tickets system (such as listing an event or purchasing a ticket), we may need additional information, which may include first name, last name, email address, physical address, business name, banking information, credit card information, PayPal information, in order to facilitate the processing of payments. 
  * **Payment Transaction Information.** Brown Paper Tickets collects information related to your payment transactions processed through the Brown Paper Tickets website, including the payment instrument used, date and time, payment amount, payment instrument expiration date and billing postcode, PayPal email address, IBAN information, your address and other related transaction details. This information is necessary for the adequate performance of the services you've agreed to when using the Brown Paper Tickets website and services. 

**1.2 Information We Automatically Collect from Your Use of the Brown Paper Tickets Website and Services**

When you visit the Brown Paper Tickets website and use the Brown Paper Tickets services, we automatically collect information, including personal information, about the services you use and how you use them. This information is necessary for the adequate performance of the Brown Paper Tickets ticketing and registration system.

  * **Geo-location Information.** When you visit the Brown Paper Tickets website, we may collect information about your approximate location as determined through data such as your IP address or mobile device's GPS to offer you an improved user experience. Most mobile devices allow you to control or disable the use of location services for applications in the device's settings menu. 
  * **Usage Information.** We collect information about your interactions with the Brown Paper Tickets webpages or content you view, your searches for events, ticket purchases or registrations, and other actions on the Brown Paper Tickets website. 
  * **Cookies and Similar Technologies.** We use cookies and other similar technologies, such as web beacons, pixels, and mobile identifiers. We may also allow our business partners to use these tracking technologies on the Brown Paper Tickets website, or engage others to track your behavior on our behalf. You may be able to disable the usage of cookies through your browser settings. For more information on our use of these technologies, see our **[Cookie Policy](https://www.brownpapertickets.com/cookies.html)**. 

* * *

**2.1 Provide, Improve, and Develop Ticketing and Registration Services on the Brown Paper Tickets Website**

  * Enable you to access and use the Brown Paper Tickets website and services. 
  * Enable you to list events and sell tickets or registrations. 
  * Purchase tickets or register for events. 
  * Operate, protect, improve, and optimize the Brown Paper Tickets experience. 
  * Provide customer service. 
  * Send you event notifications, service or support messages, updates, security alerts, and account notifications. 
  * Enforce the Payment Terms and other payment policies. 
  * Comply with legal (including banking) obligations. 

**2.2 Create and Maintain a Trusted and Secure Environment**

  * Detect and prevent fraud, spam, abuse, security incidents, and other harmful activity. 
  * Conduct security investigations and risk assessments. 
  * Comply with our legal obligations. 
  * Resolve any disputes with any of our Members and enforce our agreements with third parties. 
  * Enforce our Terms of Use and other policies. 

* * *

**3.1 With Your Consent**

Where you have provided consent, we share your information with the specific Event Organizer of the event you purchase tickets to or register for. When you purchase a ticket, your personal contact information will be provided to the Event Organizer. Brown Paper Tickets has no control over what an Event Organizer does with your information, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices or actions the Event Organizer takes outside of the Brown Paper Tickets system. Additionally, Event Organizer may choose to use analytic tools or click-through tracking from their event pages.

**3.2 Event Organizer Public Profiles, Event Listings, and Other Public Information**

The Brown Paper Tickets website lets you list events to sell tickets or register attendees. The events you list are viewable by the public, and include information you provide, such as name and contact information, which is visible to your attendees, potential attendees, and the general public. Publicly visible information may be "scraped" or indexed through third party tools or search engines. Brown Paper Tickets does not control the practices of third parties accessing your public-facing information.

**3.3 Compliance with Law, Responding to Legal Requests, Preventing Harm and Protection of Our Rights**

Brown Paper Tickets may disclose your information, including personal information, to courts, law enforcement or governmental authorities, or authorized third parties, if and to the extent we are required or permitted to do so by law, or if such disclosure is reasonably necessary: (i) to comply with our legal obligations, (ii) to comply with legal process and to respond to claims asserted against Brown Paper Tickets, (iii) to respond to verified requests relating to a criminal investigation or alleged or suspected illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any others to danger or legal liability, (iv) to enforce and administer our Terms of Service, or (v) to protect the rights, property or personal safety of Brown Paper Tickets, its employees, its Event Organizers or ticket buyers, or the general public.

**3.4 Service Providers**

Brown Paper Tickets uses a variety of third party service providers to help us provide tools and resources related to listing events and purchasing tickets through the Brown Paper Tickets website.

For example, service providers may help us provide customer service or payment services. These providers have limited access to your information to perform these tasks on our behalf and are contractually bound to protect and to use it only for the purposes for which it was disclosed and consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**3.5 Social Media**

Where permissible according to applicable law we may use certain limited personal information about you, such as your email address in an anonymized and hashed format to share with social media platforms, such as Facebook or Google, to generate leads, drive traffic to our website or otherwise promote our products and services or the Brown Paper Tickets website. These processing activities are based on our legitimate interest in undertaking marketing activities to offer you products or services that may be in your interest.

The social media platforms with which we may share your personal data are not controlled or supervised by Brown Paper Tickets. Therefore, any questions regarding how your social media platform service provider processes your personal data should be directed to such provider.

**3.6 Business Transfers**

If Brown Paper Tickets undertakes or is involved in any merger, acquisition, reorganization, sale of assets, bankruptcy, or insolvency event, then we may sell, transfer or share some or all of our information in connection with such transaction or in contemplation of such transaction (e.g., due diligence). In this event, we will notify you before your personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

* * *

The Brown Paper Tickets system may contain links to third party websites or services, such as third party integrations, co-branded services, or third party-branded services ("Third Party Partners"). Brown Paper Tickets does not own or control these Third Party Partners, and when you interact with them, you may be providing information directly to the Third Party Partner. These Third Party Partners will have their own rules about the collection, use, and disclosure of information. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of the other websites you visit.

* * *

You may exercise any of the rights described in this section on our [Request to Removal Personal Data](https://www.brownpapertickets.com/data-removal-request.html) page. Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before taking further action on your request, and we will need to keep a record of your request.

**5.1 Managing Your Information**

You may access and update some of your information through your Brown Paper Tickets account settings. You are responsible for keeping your personal information up-to-date on your Brown Paper Tickets account.

**5.2 Rectification of Inaccurate or Incomplete Information**

You have the right to ask us to correct inaccurate or incomplete personal information we have and which you cannot update yourself on your Brown Paper Tickets account.

**5.3 Data Access and Portability**

In some jurisdictions, applicable law may entitle you to request copies of your personal information held by us. You may also be entitled to request copies of personal information that you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format and/or request us to transmit this information to another service provider where it is technically feasible.

**5.4 Data Retention and Erasure**

We generally retain your personal information for as long as is necessary to provide ticketing and registration services for you and to comply with our legal obligations. You have the right to request erasure of your information. Please note that if you request the erasure of your personal information:

  * If you have purchased a ticket or registered for an event, Brown Paper Tickets cannot remove your information before the completion of the event for business and fraud prevention purposes. 
  * We may retain some of your personal information as necessary for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud detection and prevention and enhancing safety. For example, if we suspend a Brown Paper Tickets account for fraud or safety reasons, we may retain certain information from that account to prevent the opening of a new Brown Paper Tickets account in the future. 
  * We may retain and use your personal information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations. For example, Brown Paper Tickets may keep some of your information for tax, legal reporting and auditing obligations. 
  * Some copies of your information (e.g., log records) may remain in our database, but are disassociated from personal identifiers. 
  * Because we maintain the Brown Paper Tickets website to protect from accidental or malicious loss and destruction, residual copies of your personal information may not be removed from our backup systems for a limited period of time. 

**5.5 Withdrawing Consent**

Where you have provided your consent to the processing of your personal information by Brown Paper Tickets, you may withdraw your consent at any time by changing the information on your account, adjusting your Account settings, or by sending a communication to Brown Paper Tickets specifying which consent you are withdrawing. Please note that the withdrawal of your consent does not affect the lawfulness of any processing activities based on such consent before its withdrawal.

* * *

Brown Paper Tickets operates globally and stores information in the United States. Laws and regulations vary from country to country and may differ from the laws applicable to your Country of Residence. For example, information collected within the European Economic Area (EEA) may be transferred, stored, and processed outside of the EEA for business purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Where we transfer, store, and process your personal information outside of the EEA we have ensured that appropriate safeguards are in place to ensure an adequate level of data protection.

* * *

Brown Paper Tickets is continuously implementing and updating administrative, technical, and physical security measures to help protect your information against unauthorized access, loss, destruction, or alteration. Some of the safeguards we use to protect your information are firewalls and data encryption, information access controls and annual PCI-DSS audits. Currently, Brown Paper Tickets is PCI-DSS v3.2 Level 1 certified. You can learn more about the PCI-DSS security standards here: <https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/>

If you know or have reason to believe that the information you provided to Brown Paper Tickets has been stolen, misappropriated, or otherwise compromised, please contact us following the instructions in the Contact Us section below.

* * *

Brown Paper Tickets reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time in accordance with this provision. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the revised Privacy Policy on the Brown Paper Tickets website and update the "Effective date" at the top of this Privacy Policy. If you disagree with the revised Privacy Policy, you may cancel your Account or contact us to remove your information. Once any new Privacy Policy is published, you will be required to consent to it before continued use of our website.

* * *

If you have any questions or complaints about this Privacy Policy or Brown Paper Tickets' information handling practices, you may email us at legal@brownpapertickets.com or contact us at:

Brown Paper Tickets, LLC  
220 Nickerson St  
Seattle, WA 98109  
United States  
Phone: 800-838-3006  
legal@brownpapertickets.com 

Or:

Brown Paper Tickets LTD  
17-19 Maritime Lane  
EDINBURGH  
EH6 6RZ  
United Kingdom  
Phone: 0800 411 8881  
legal@brownpapertickets.com
